Finding Aid for Jennifer Granholm papers, 1992-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Office of the First Gentleman
  - Staff Files (Joan Bowman)
    - Michigan State University Extension -- Mentoring undated (Box 218)
    - Michigan Trial Lawyers Association (MTLA) 2005 (Box 218)
    - Michigan at Risk Taping 2006 (Box 218)
    - Michigan Connections 2003-2004 (Box 218)
    - Michigan Press Association 2006 (Box 218)
    - Michigan Radio Network 2003-2004 (Box 218)
    - Small Business/Michigan Retirement 2006 (Box 218)
    - Michigan Rx 2006 (Box 218)
    - Michigan Steps Up 2006 (Box 218)
    - Michigan Youth Leadership Forum (Students with Disabilities) 2005 (Box 218)
    - Michigan Sheriff Event, Grand Rapids 2006 (Box 218)
    - Minimum Wage, Grand Rapids 2006 (Box 218)
    - Mentor Bridgewalk -- Mentoring: A Running Start 2006 (Box 218)
    - Misdemeanors and Miracle of Mentoring 2005 (Box 218)
    - Lunch -- Muskegon Heights, Faith-Based Program 2003 (Box 218)
    - Muskegon 2003 (Box 218)
    - National Civilian Community Corps (NCCC), AmeriCorps 2006 (Box 218)
    - National Faith-Based Initiative 2004 (Box 218)
    - National Mentoring Center 2003 (Box 218)
    - New Hope Missionary Baptist Church -- Violence Forum, Grand Rapids 2006 (Box 218)
    - New Life Guidance Center 2005 (Box 218)
    - NMM -- Mentor Michigan 2007 (Box 218)
    - Ottawa County Mentoring Collaborative, Grand Haven 2007 (Box 218)
    - PACE -- Communication: Breakthrough to Understanding 2004 (Box 218)
    - National Guard Youth Challenge 2005-2006 (Box 218)
    - Emergency Management 2004 (Box 218)
    - Official City Prep Program 2004 (Box 218)
    - Pathfinders, Muskegon Heights 2006 (Box 218)
    - Positive Male Role Models 2005 (Box 218)
    - 2-1-1 Call Centers 2005 (Box 218)
    - Project Blue Star -- Phase II 2005-2006 (Box 218)
    - Project Blue Star 2005 (Box 218)
    - Project Cool -- Rev. Moody, Grand Rapids 2007 (Box 218)
    - Recognizing Achievement, Rewarding Excellence (RARE): Everyday Heroes 2006 (Box 218)
    - Prudential Spirit of Community Awards 2004 (Box 218)
    - Reach Out and Read 2007 (Box 218)
    - RSVPs for Senior Volunteer Program 2004 (Box 218)
    - Read for Life 2006-2007 (Box 218)
    - Spinning Physical and Renewable Kinetic Living Energy (SPARKLE), Grand Valley State University 2005 (Box 218)
    - Grand Rapids Rotary 2006 (Box 218)
    - Stopping Time -- Department of Corrections 2006 (Box 218)
    - Strive Program -- Rotary Affiliation 2004 (Box 218)
    - Super Sunday 2005 (Box 218)
    - Sylvia Rubach -- Motivational Speaker 2004 (Box 218)
    - Target undated (Box 218)
    - Trade Event, Grand Rapids 2006 (Box 218)
    - Transit Bill Sign, Grand Rapids 2006 (Box 218)
    - Tuesday Toolman 2006 (Box 218)
    - United Food and Commercial Workers 951 Union Center 2006 (Box 218)
    - United Way 2-1-1 and Facts, Grand Rapids 2007 (Box 218)
    - USDA Rural Development 2004-2005 (Box 218)
    - Violence Forum, Grand Rapids 2006 (Box 218)
    - Military Family Initiative 2004-2005 (Box 218)
    - Videocassettes (VHS)
      - “On Being ‘First Dad’,” First Gentleman Dan Mulhern on WJBK FOX2 2005 (Box 218)
      - Governor’s Art Awards, Detroit Public TV 2003 (Box 218)
      - Mentor Michigan Public Service Announcements undated (Box 218)
  - Staff Files (various)
    - Correspondence 2003-2006, 3 folders (Box 219)
    - Paul Harris Fellow Award undated (Box 219)
    - Michigan Prisoner Reentry Initiative (MPRI) Mentoring Banquet (includes comments by Governor Granholm and highlights from event hosted by Pastor Terry Williams) 2008
    - Western Michigan Men’s Outreach (WMMO) Promotional Video 2009
      - Edited Version
      - Full-length Version
    - “Mentor Michigan,” Media Meet 535 2005, VHS Cassette (Box 219)
    - Personal Correspondence 2005-2006 (Box 219)
    - National Governor’s Association -- Spouses Health Initiative 2005 (Box 219)
    - Spouses Retreat 2003-2005 (Box 219)
    - National Governor’s Association -- Spouses Assistants 2003 (Box 219)
    - Spring Lake District Library 2005 (Box 219)
    - GRPI/Jane Weiss -- Great Place to Work Business Meeting 2004 (Box 219)
    - 100 Best Places to Work 2003 (Box 219)
    - Leadership in Tough Times 2003 (Box 219)
    - Speech Notes 2005-2006 (Box 219)
    - AmeriCorps 2009 (Box 219)
    - Michigan Community Service Commission 2009 (Box 219)
    - Reform Proposals 2010 (Box 219)
    - Governor’s Council on Physical Fitness, Health and Sports 2007-2010 (Box 219)
    - Yeshiva Beth Yehuda Annual Dinner Photographs 1999 (Box 219)
    - Office Decoration undated (Box 219)
    - Michigan’s Next Great Companies (NGC) Project
      - Case Studies 2007 (Box 219)
      - Prospects 2007 (Box 219)
      - Core Group Meeting July 2007 (Box 219)
      - Core Group Meeting August 2007 (Box 219)
      - University of Michigan Center for Positive Organizational Scholarship Presentation 2007 (Box 219)
      - GPTWI Presentation 2007 (Box 219)
      - Mary Kramer Presentation September 2007 (Box 219)
      - Task Plan circa 2006 (Box 219)
    - Big Brothers/Big Sisters 2003-2004 (Box 219)
    - Adequate Yearly Progress Schools 2003 (Box 219)
    - The Governor’s Cabinet -- The Heart of Leadership for the State of Michigan undated (Box 219)
    - Mulhern Family Tree undated (Box 219)
    - Tuesday Toolmen Volunteers: Providing Service in Every Community 2005, 2 folders (Box 219)
    - Staff Lunch 2004 (Box 219)
    - Bridgewalk 2004 (Box 219)
    - Photographs of Dan Mulhern and Jennifer Granholm at Various Events undated (Box 219)
    - Mentor Michigan
      - Paper Files
        (See Digital Files for related content)
        - Index of Mentor Michigan Digital Materials circa 2010 (Box 220)
        - Mentoring Census: Overview of Results 2010 (Box 220)
        - National Guard Mobilizing Mentors Campaign: Brochure circa 2008 (Box 220)
        - Providers Council: Quality Program Standards for Youth Mentoring circa 2005 (Box 220)
        - Men in Mentoring Toolkit Description 2009 (Box 220)
        - Michelle Obama Event: Press Release 2010 (Box 220)
        - Mentor Michigan E-Newsletter (overview and sample) 2009 (Box 220)
        - John Hancock Financial Services Essay Contest 2008 (Box 220)
        - Mighty Mac Swim Press Release 2007 (Box 220)
        - Brochures and Flyers 2009-2010, 2 folders (Box 220)
        - News Clippings: Mackinac Bridge Run 2006 (Box 220)
        - Engler Administration Transition Materials 2002, Originally housed in a binder (Box 220)
        - Faith-Based and Other Mentoring Resources 2003 (Box 220)
        - Mentor Michigan Summit: Child’s Hope 2003 (Box 220)
        - Corporate Guide for Mentoring 2004 (Box 220)
        - Volunteers in Prevention (VIP, Wayne County Partner in Mentor Michigan) 2003 (Box 220)
      - Digital Files
        (See Paper Files for related content)
        - AmeriCorps Program 2010
        - Brochures and Flyers (Graphic Art Files) 2003-2004
        - Governor’s Service Awards
          - Programs and Forms 2004-2010
          - Fox Theater Awards Event and Video Tributes 2006
          - Margaret Yake (Project Blessing Founder) 2007
          - Olivia Thomas (Youth Volunteer Tribute) 2008
        - Leadership Council 2006-2007
        - Lloyd Carr MVP Awards 2010
        - Meijer Mini Grants 2008-2010
        - Mentor Michigan Strategic Plan 2010
        - Mentoring Census Data 2004-2009
        - Michelle Obama Event: Video 2010
        - Michigan’s Premiere Mentoring Conference: Registration and Brochures 2006-2010
        - National Guard Mobilizing Mentors Campaign: Video circa 2008
        - National Mentoring Month/Michigan Mentoring Month 2004-2010
        - Providers Council: Contact Lists, Nomination Forms, and Roles and Responsibilities 2004-2010
    - Mentor Michigan
      - Digital Files
        - Public Service Announcements (PSAs)
          - Governor’s Appeal 2008
          - Fox Sports Network-Detroit “High School Hammer Time” (includes Lloyd Carr PSA) 2006
          - Lloyd Carr 2005
          - Multiple announcements, featuring Chauncey Billups (Detroit Pistons), Dan Mulhern, and Dennis Archer 2005
        - Regional Training 2004-2005
        - Summits 2003
        - Volunteers in Prevention (VIP, Wayne County Mentor Michigan Partner): Walking Kids Back from the Edge 2001
    - Lansing Area Manufacturing Partnership 2002, 2004 (Box 220)
    - Kent County Education Association -- Reception for Superintendents, etc 2006 (Box 220)
    - Big Brothers/Big Sisters 2004 (Box 220)
    - Big Brothers, Big Sisters Bowl for Kids 2006 (Box 220)
    - Greater Lansing Big Brothers, Big Sisters 2004 (Box 220)
    - Family Mentoring Network circa 2004 (Box 220)
    - Habitat for Humanity Mentors 2005 (Box 220)
    - Journey Mentoring Program 2004 (Box 220)
    - Skilled Trades Mentoring 2003-2005 (Box 220)
    - Jobs Event, Grand Rapids 2005 (Box 220)
    - Mayor’s Time 2004-2005 (Box 220)
    - Mentor Connection 2005 (Box 220)
    - Menttium 100 2007 (Box 220)
    - Metro Detroit’s Promise 2003 (Box 220)
    - Mid-Michigan Mentoring Celebration 2007 (Box 220)
    - National Governor’s Association Meeting for New Governors and Spouses 2002 (Box 220)
    - Public Speaking Resource Binder 2006 (Box 220)
    - PowerPoint Slides from Presentations 2003-2004 (Box 220)
    - Governor’s Residence Foundation 2007, 4 folders (Box 220)
    - National Governors Association Spouses Program 2006 (Box 220)
    - Governor’s Residence 2003 (Box 221)
    - Daniel Granholm Mulhern (DGM) Vitae -- Events and Activities 2003-2005 (Box 221)
    - Michigan Christmas Tree Association 2004 (Box 221)
    - Holiday Cards undated (Box 221)
    - Media Clippings 2003-2007 (Box 221)
    - Miscellaneous 2003-2010, 2 folders (Box 221)
      (scattered)
    - National Governors Association -- New Governors School 2006, 2 folders (Box 221)
    - Photographs of First Gentleman Daniel G. Mulhern and Governor Jennifer M. Granholm undated (Box 221)
    - National Governors Association Photographs 2010, undated (Box 221)
  - Audio-visual Materials
    - Videocassettes (VHS)
      - 2001-2002
        - “MI Leaders’ Roundtable on Political Civility,” C.M.U.’s Griffin Policy Forum 2001 (Box 221)
        - “Walking Troubled Kids Back from the Edge,” VIP Mentoring 2001 (Box 221)
        - Family Matters,” Interview with Governor Granholm and First Gentleman Daniel Mulhern on CNN: American Morning with Paul Zahn 2002 (Box 221)
      - 2003
        - “9th Annual Governor’s Education Summit,” Michigan Foundation for Education Leadership (Box 222)
        - “Celebrating the Role of Men in Michigan’s Families,” First Man’s Forum (Box 222)
        - “First Gentleman Daniel Mulhern and MSU Women’s Basketball Coach,” Michigan Education Trust News Clips (Box 222)
        - “First Man’s Forum,” Comcast Edit (Box 222)
        - “First Man’s Forums,” TV3, 8, and 17 (Box 222)
        - “Insight,” Daniel Mulhern, CMV Public Televisions (Box 222)
        - MDOT Leadership Conference (Box 222)
        - “A Message from Governor Jennifer M. Granholm and Her Husband Daniel Mulhern on the 2003 Governor Service Awards” (Box 222)
        - “Michigan’s First Gentleman,” MGTV Forum (Box 222)
        - “Stay at Home Dads,” Interview with the First Gentleman, WZZM 13 News (Box 222)
        - Vision and Values Message, Jennifer Granholm (Box 222)
      - 2004
        - “Build on the Past, focus on the Future,” MDOT Leadership Conference (Box 222)
        - Comcast Newsmakers: Daniel Mulhern (Box 222)
        - Dan Mulhern -- Ford Leadership Programs Quarterly, Ford Motor Company (Box 222)
        - “Governor Granholm and First Gentleman Mulhern Recognize ‘National Thank Your Mentor Day,’” Press Conference (Box 222)
        - Governor Granholm at Emily’s List Lunch (Box 222)
        - National Student/Parent Mock Election Extravaganza, Michigan Government Television Network (Box 222)
        - “On Being the First Gentleman” Daniel Mulhern on UPN Action News Detroit (Box 222)
        - “Unplugged,” Value in Leadership (Box 222)
      - 2005
        - Comcast Newsmakers: Daniel Mulhern (Box 179)
        - Rotary 100th Birthday -- Daniel Mulhern Speech and Award Presentation (Box 179)
        - Dearborn Journal 14 (Box 179)
        - Fathers Matter Forum -- Luncheon Speaker (Dan G. Mulhern) & Legislative Update (Senator Hardiman) (Box 179)
        - Comcast Newsmakers -- “Leadership/New Economy,” Mackinaw Policy Conference (Box 179)
        - MCTA Luncheon Video, Michigan Government Television Network (Box 179)
        - Michigan Hispanic Chamber of Commerce (Box 179)
        - Consumer’s Corner -- “MSHDA-Homeless Awareness Week” (Box 179)
        - Off The Record 531 -- “One on One: Michigan First Gentleman Dan Mulhern” (Box 179)
        - “Talk Early Talk Often” Edit with Text and Music -- Version with Revised Answer (Box 179)
      - 2006
        - Comcast Newsmakers: Dan Mulhern (Box 179)
      - Undated
        - Commander in Chief (Box 179)
        - Raw Footage: Daniel Mulhern at City of Dearborn (Box 179)
        - Spotlight on the News -- Daniel G. Mulhern (Box 179)
    - Audiocassette
      - Hutchinson Elementary School First Graders Reading to Daniel G. Mulhern (Box 179)
    - Digital Materials
      - First Gentleman Dan Mulhern Portraits (Ameen Howrani) 2003
      - Governor Granholm Portrait: Election Night Victory 2006
      - Granholm: First Governor to Tour the Mackinac Bridge Towers October 4, 2008
      - Hands on Michigan Governor’s Service Awards (Act One: Rough Cut) 2006
      - Interview with Governor Granholm on CNN’s State of the Union with Candy Crowley 2010
      - Michigan Governor’s Service Awards 2006
      - WGVU Newsmakers: Dan Mulhern 2007
      - Women Pastor Breakfast with the Governor 2006, DVD
  - General Office Records
    - General 2004-2007
    - Best Places to Work 2005, 2007
    - Biography 2003-2010, 2 folders
    - Detroit Marathon, Superstar Relay 2005
    - News Clippings 2004, 2006-2007
    - Leadership Materials 2003-2004
    - Press Releases 2003
    - Event Feedback 2007
    - First Spouse 2003, 2006
    - First Man Forums
      - First Man Forum, Detroit 2003
      - First Man Forum, Grand Rapids 2003
    - Governor’s Service Award 2004-2006
    - Great Workplace Initiative 2004-2005
    - Joan Bowman (West Michigan Regional Director)
      - General 2003-2007
      - First Man Forum 2003
      - Photographs 2004, 2006
      - Military
        - Project Blue Star 2005
        - Youth Challenge 2005
      - One Michigan Foundation 2004-2007
      - Residence Issues and Letter 2003
    - Michigan Community Service Commission (MCSC) 2003-2009
    - Mentor Michigan
      - General 2004-2006
      - Area Opportunities 2004-2005
      - Adequate Yearly Progress (AYP) Information 2004
      - Background Check Information 2003-2004
      - Big Brothers, Big Sisters 2004
      - Borders 2003, 2005
      - Campus Compact 2004-2005
      - Collaborating Organizations 2005
      - Corporate Materials 2004-2006
      - Kahle Consulting Materials 2004-2006
      - Faith-Based Information 2004-2006
      - Fast Facts for Events 2005
      - Forms and Handouts 2004-2006
      - Funding 2004
      - Tri-Michigan Initiative 2005
      - Leadership Detroit Project 2004-2005
      - Leadership Council 2005-2006
      - Letters
        - General 2003-2006
        - Mentoring Interest 2003
        - Op-Eds 2005
      - Logos 2003, 2005
      - Marketing and Media 2003-2006
      - Public Service Announcements
        - General 2008
        - Old Public Service Announcements 2008
        - Script Templates 2007-2008
        - Biographies of Celebrities 2008
        - Request Letters 2008
      - National Mentoring Partnerships 2005
      - National Mentoring Month 2004
      - National Mentoring Month 2005
      - National Mentoring Month 2006
      - National Mentoring Month 2007
      - One Michigan Award 2005
      - Providers Council 2005-2007
      - Summits 2003
      - Summits 2004
      - Summits 2006
      - General Talking Points 2005-2006
      - Training Information 2004
    - Michigan Education Trust (MET) 2003
    - Military Projects
      - Project Blue Star 2005
      - Youth Challenge 2005
    - Next Great Companies
      - Case Studies 2007
      - Communication 2007
      - Core Team Meetings 2007
      - Graphics 2007
      - Miscellaneous 2007
      - Notes 2007
      - Presentations 2007
      - Recruitment 2007
      - Sloan Awards 2009
    - Next Great Workplace Project
      - General 2007-2008
      - CEO Forums
        - 2008-2009
      - Core Team Meetings 2008
      - Next Great Companies
        - Awards Program 2008
        - CEO Forums 2008
          - General
          - Mackinac Policy Conference
        - State Conference 2008
        - Website 2008
          - Phase I
          - Final
        - Advisory Group Meetings
          - 2007
          - Core Team 2008
        - Archive
          - CEO 2 CEO Forums 2007
          - Communication 2007-2008
          - Core Team Meetings 2007-2008
          - Fortune 2008
          - General 2008
          - Graphics 2007
          - Multidisciplinary Application Projects (MAP) Application 2007
          - Miscellaneous Before Kasey Items 2008
          - Recruitment 2008
          - Stakeholder-Sponsor Meetings 2007
          - Task Plans 2007-2008
        - Case Studies 2007-2008
        - Letters 2008
        - Marketing Materials 2008
        - Reference Materials
        - General 2007-2008
        - Incubators 2008
        - Dan Mulhern’s Documents 2007-2008
        - Planning and Data 2008
      - Presentation Materials 2008
      - Research
        - General 2008
        - Innovation Zones 2008
      - November Summit 2008
      - Website Materials 2008
    - Physical Fitness Council 2005-2006
    - Presentations
      - General 2003-2009 (scattered)
      - Speeches 2003-2005
      - Spiritual Talks 2004-2005
    - Residence 2004-2009 (scattered), 2 folders
    - State of Michigan Employee Communications 2006-2007
    - Speech Information and Statistics 2005-2008
    - Speeches
      - General 2003-2009
      - PowerPoints 2003-2006
      - Vision and Values 2004
      - Youth and Adults 2004
    - Everyday Leadership Speeches 2005-2008
    - Super Bowl 2004
    - Tuesday Toolmen, Affordable Senior Home Repair 2006
    - Vision and Values 2004-2005
- Archived Websites
  The Archived Websites series contains archived copies of the Governor's Executive Orders as presented on the state's official Website as well as archived versions of her post-gubernatorial Website. This latter site includes news and events, press releases, an overview of Granholm's career and governorship and documents her social media activities.
  - Executive Orders
    - 2003
    - 2004
    - 2005
    - 2006
    - 2007
    - 2008
    - 2009-2010
  - Jennifer Granholm gubernatorial Website
    - May 16, 2007, .ZIP file
    - February 15, 2008 capture
    - February 16, 2009 capture
  - Jennifer Granholm gubernatorial Website, 2010
  - Jennifer Granholm Post-gubernatorial Website, 2011
- Memorabilia
  The Memorabilia series contains objects presented to both Jennifer Granholm and Daniel Mulhern and includes a quilt made for governor by women in the Upper Peninsula and banner from the First Man's Forum as well as awards and certificates.
  - Trophies and souvenirs related to the Governor Granholm’s achievements and public activities (Box 223)
  - Awards, certificates, and gifts from constituents related to First Gentleman Mulhern’s achievements and public activities (Box 224)
  - Awards, certificates, and gifts from constituents related to First Gentleman Mulhern’s achievements and public activities (Box 225)
    (continued)
  - Quilt made for governor by women in Upper Peninsula (Box 226)
  - Banner from the First Man’s Forum (Box 227)
  - 4 framed awards and certificates of Daniel Mulhern and 3 framed awards and certificates of Governor Granholm (Object 1)
  - 4 framed awards and certificates of Daniel Mulhern and 3 framed awards and certificates of Governor Granholm (Object 2)
  - 4 framed awards and certificates of Daniel Mulhern and 3 framed awards and certificates of Governor Granholm (Object 3)
  - 4 framed awards and certificates of Daniel Mulhern and 3 framed awards and certificates of Governor Granholm (Object 4)
  - 4 framed awards and certificates of Daniel Mulhern and 3 framed awards and certificates of Governor Granholm (Object 5)
  - 4 framed awards and certificates of Daniel Mulhern and 3 framed awards and certificates of Governor Granholm (Object 6)
  - 4 framed awards and certificates of Daniel Mulhern and 3 framed awards and certificates of Governor Granholm (Object 7)